Khoa D. Doan

★ khoadoan.me

☑ khoadoan@vt.edu

ABOUT

My research aims to understand the characteristics of existing algorithms in practical applications and develop Machine learning models that can be used in practice with low computational complexity and less human effort. My research focuses on the development of these algorithms for a variety of areas, such as Machine Learning, E-commerce, Computer Vision, and Artificial Intelligence (AI) Security. I am also interested in understanding the gap between existing theory and practice, and scale out/up algorithms in real-world environments.

EDUCATION

Ph.D in Computer Science

Virginia Tech (VT)

MS in Computer Science

University of Maryland, College Park (UMCP)

BS in Computer Science with a Minor in Mathematics

Webster University

GPA: 4.0/4.0

Virginia, USA August 2021

College Park, Maryland, USA

August 2010-May 2015

Saint Louis, Missouri, USA

August 2003-May 2006

EMPLOYMENT

Research Scientist - Baidu Research USA, Seattle, WA

2020-

 Perform fundamental research in Generative Modeling, especially Generative Adversarial Models (GANs) and Deep Energy-based Generative Models, Deep Hashing Models and AI Security.

Researcher - Criteo AI Lab, Palo Alto, CA

2019-2020

Perform research in Generative Modeling, especially Generative Adversarial Models (GANs).
Besides investigating their theoretical aspects, I studied the applications of generative models into several problem domains, including computational look-alike modeling in advertising, learning to hash for text and images, and regression.

Graduate Research Assistant – Virginia Tech

2016-

Senior Data Scientist - Verve Mobile

2014-2019

- Be the principle data scientist behind Verve's Momentum-product ¹ which build highly-scalable statistical models of measuring the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. This is a fully-automatic platform that aggregates user-interaction data from multiple, large-scale data sources, build counterfactual models to estimate the *incremental KPIs* of the selected advertising campaigns, and exposes the analytical results to Verve's customers.
- Be a part of the Audience Modeling Team which is responsible for building production-ready predictive models such as Age, Gender, Home Associations, etc... Responsible for modeling the core algorithms behind Verve's Audience System.
- Be a part of the team that builds the core, patented Home Association algorithm at Verve (see below).

https://www.verve.com/products/momentum/

• Be a part of the Data Infrastructure Team that design the underlying architecture of the company's data-warehouse/data-analytic platform on Amazon AWS, which is later migrated to Google GCP.

Faculty Research Associate – University of Maryland, College Park

2013-2015

- Participate in high performance system research.
- Involve in Automated Event Service (AES) and Data Environment For Rapid Exploration And Characterization Of Hydrometeorological Organized Systems (DERECHOS) research projects at NASA.
- Responsible for development of large scale data (statistical) analysis algorithms in distributed environments such as Hadoop, Spark, Cassandra, and SciDB.

Data Scientist (Consultant) – B3Intelligence

2014-2015

- Develop a statistical NLP topic model to categorize different types of survey text responses.
- Develop an attribution model to understand the relationship between the topics being discussed by the respondents and the expected sentiment in these responses.

Research Associate - NASA

2012-2014

- Participate in high performance, distributed system research on NASA large-scale, remotesensing data.
- Perform research in manifold learning in large-scale environments.
- Involve in Automated Event Service (AES) and Data Environment For Rapid Exploration And Characterization Of Hydrometeorological Organized Systems (DERECHOS) research projects at NASA.
- Responsible for development of large scale data (statistical) analysis algorithms in distributed environments such as Hadoop, Spark, Cassandra, and SciDB.

Teaching Assistant – University of Maryland, College Park

2010-2011

Senior Developer – US Department of Energy/Department of Veteran Affairs

2008-2014

- Lead application development activities.
- Integration of Open Source API's into existing system architecture.

HONORS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Criteo Research Award – Virginia Tech	2018
NSF Urban Computing Fellowship – Virginia Tech	2016
Graduation Honor, Summer Cum Laude – Webster University	2006
Regional ACM Collegiate Computing Contest Honor – Webster University	2004
University Scholarship – Webster University	2003

PUBLICATIONS

- 16. **K. D. Doan**, Y. Lao, & P. Li, "Backdoor Attack with Imperceptible Input and Latent Modification". *Thirty-fifth Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems* 2021 (NeurIPS).
- 15. **K. D. Doan**, Y. Lao, W. Zhao, & P. Li, "LIRA: Learnable, Imperceptible and Robust Backdoor Attacks". 2021 IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV).
- 14. **K. D. Doan***, S. Manchanda*, S. Mahapatra, & CK. Reddy, "Interpretable Graph Similarity Computation via Differentiable Optimal Alignment of Node Embeddings", *In Proceedings of*

^{*} Equal Contribution

- International ACM SIGIR conference on research and development in Information Retrieval 2021 (SIGIR).
- 13. **K. D. Doan**, S. Tan, W. Zhao, & P. Li, "Fast Neural Learning-to-Hash Ranking under Neural Network based Measures". *Under Submission*.
- 12. **K. D. Doan**, F. Wang, S. Manchanda, S. Selvaraj, A. Bhowmilk & CK. Reddy, "Image Generation via Minimizing Fréchet Distance in Discriminator Feature Space. *Under Submission*.
- 11. K. D. Doan, S. Badirli, & CK. Reddy, "Generative Hashing Network". Under Submission.
- 10. **K. D. Doan**, S. Manchanda, S. Badirli, & C. K. Reddy. "Image Hashing by Minimizing Discrete Component-wise Wasserstein Distance". *Under Submission*.
- 9. **K. D. Doan**, J. Xie, W. Zhao, & P. Li, "Generative Cooperative Hashing Network". *Under Submission*.
- 8. S. Badirli, X. Liu, **K. D. Doan**, Z. Xing, A. Bhowmik & SS. Keerthi. Gradient Boosting Neural Networks: GrowNet. *Under Submission*.
- 7. S. Manchanda, **K. Doan** & SS Keerthi. Regression via Implicit Models and Optimal Transport Cost Minimization. *https://arxiv.org/abs/2003.01296*.
- 6. **K. Doan** & C. K. Reddy. Efficient Implicit Unsupervised Text Hashing using Adversarial Autoencoder. *In Proceedings of The Web Conference*, 2020 (WWW).
- 5. S. Manchanda, P. Yadav, K. Doan, & K. Sathiya. Targeted display advertising: the case of preferential attachment. *In Proceedings of International Conference on Big Data*, 2019.
- 4. **K. Doan**, P. Yadav & C. K. Reddy. Adversarial Factorization Autoencoder for Look-alike Modeling. *In Proceedings of ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management*, 2019 (CIKM).
- 3. **K. Doan**, G. Yang & C. K. Reddy. An Attentive Spatio-Temporal Neural Model for Successive Point Of Interest Recommendation. In Proceedings of Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, 2019.
- 2. **K. Doan**, A. O. Oloso, K. S. Kuo, T. L. Clune, H. Yu, B. Nelson, & J. Zhang. Evaluating the impact of data placement to Spark and SciDB with an earth science use case. *In Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Big Data*, 2016.
- 1. **K. Doan**, A. O. Oloso, K. S. Kuo & T. L. Clune (2014, December). Performance comparison of big-data technologies in locating intersections in satellite ground tracks. *In Proceedings of ASE BigData Conference*, 2014.

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Program Committee (Invited)

- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR): 2021
- Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS): 2020-2021
- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML): 2020-2021
- Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR): 2020-2022
- International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV): 2021

- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV): 2020
- AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI): 2021-2022
- IEEE International Conference on Big Data (BigData): 2020
- 1st International Workshop on Industrial Recommendation Systems (IRS): 2020-2021

Journal Reviewer

- ACM Transactions on Internet Technology (TOIT): 2020
- ACMD Transactions on Knowledge Discovery from Data (TKDD): 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021

Conference Reviewer

- ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining (KDD): 2017, 2018, 2019
- ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM): 2017, 2018, 2019
- ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM): 2017, 2018, 2019
- The Web Conference (WWW): 2017, 2018, 2019
- International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI): 2017, 2018, 2019

Talks/Presentations

- **K. Doan**. Generative models meet similarity search (*Seminar*). Baidu Cognitive Computing Lab, USA, 2020.
- K. Doan, B. Cave & C. K. Reddy (*Poster*). CrimeLab: A data-driven approach. Virginia Tech Urban Computing Day, 2017.
- H. Avik, G. Takahara & D. Khoa (Talk). Social Media Analytics using Bayesian Multistate Intensity Models. 43rd Annual Meeting of the Statistical Society of Canada. https://bit.ly/ 3extrE

PATENTS

B. E. Crook, **K. Doan**, G. K. Ng, C. G. Nicotra, M. J. Wrona. Systems, methods, and apparatus for reverse geocoding. US Patent US20160330592A1.

TEACHING

Data Analytics – Virginia Tech	2019
Deep Learning – Virginia Tech	2018
Operating Systems – University of Maryland, College Park	2012
Organization of Programming Language – University of Maryland, College Park	2011
Computer Architecture – University of Maryland, College Park	2011
Discrete Mathematics – University of Maryland, College Park	2010
Compiler Analysis – University of Maryland, College Park	2010